Welcome to Eurofly. Training. Charter flight training. Hello everyone, warm greetings and let
me welcome you finally to the first ever official English demonstration of a real-time flight in
Eurofly 3, which is exactly what you'll be witnessing right now. And in case you're
listening to this or watching this at the time it's been published, you'll be probably very
interested in this because Eurofly 3, the new version, the long-anticipated version, is actually
coming soon. And by that I mean really soon, like within a matter of days or weeks at worst. So stay
tuned.
To those of you who've been expecting it, I'm really glad to be here, to be able to be here
finally. And I actually mean it because I'm aware, just like everyone else on the development team
is aware, that you've been waiting for this really for ages and that there's been several
promises, even if maybe just tentative ones, but still promises over the years that it's going to
come, you know, to be released.
Really soon. And yeah, there's been a delay, but just now we're finally about to release it. And still, it's
never come until now. So we're glad to be able to tell you that it's finally here. Everyone on the team
actually believed those promises at the time we made them. But as you as I'm sure many of you can imagine,
real life things often like to get in the way and busy schedules and families and other duties at work and
at other places and so on. But let's not delve into this very much because this is no longer the case. It's
actually here or almost here. It may have been released already by the time you're watching this. So let's not
talk about the past. Let's talk about the present and the future. To those of you who may be coming to
Eurofly 3 for the first time, when hearing this, you may have never experienced the previous versions of the
game before.
I hope this is going to be as useful as it is to those who know what Eurofly is all about because they've played it
before and they can't wait to actually get their hands on the new features and on the changes on the new version of
the game. So as you've probably heard, or guessed by now, even those of you who haven't played it before, Eurofly is
an actual flight simulator, an audio simulator for the blind and visually impaired.
So you will be flying and controlling a real aircraft, real plane. There's over 150 of them in total, I believe, different planes, and
you'll be flying on the real world map, an actual real accurate representation of the Earth, including all the various airports in the
different countries that exist out there.
So it's partly a game, but it's also a game.
It's fundamentally an Amanda blends to play.
map uh i'll be demonstrating everything and showing and explaining everything as though
no one none of you have played eurofly before because there have been so many things that are
new and different and changed in version three that essentially nothing has remained the same
except maybe for just a few basic keystrokes so even if you knew how to fly a plane in version
2 even backwards you know you will still have to re-learn everything from scratch as though
you were a completely newbie pilot so as you can hear we are already in the main menu and
we've been welcomed by new jingle those of you who may have known the previous versions have
most certainly noticed this and there are several different jingles in version 3 now
we're going to get a different one every time we start the game so
the welcome
is actually going to be slightly different every time and by the way before i get started
with anything let me just briefly emphasize and also apologize for my english because
as i'm sure you can hear it's not my native language it's my second language
so let me apologize in advance for any mistakes i may make when recording this and that i'm
almost bound to make actually because i can tell you it's pretty difficult to
but i'm not trying to use this as an excuse but just as just as an explanation it's pretty
difficult to actually be flying a plane at the same time you really have to concentrate on a
lot of different things all at once and to be talking over it at the same time
so let's hope i'm not going to make any mistakes uh cross my across your fingers
for me if you can and wish me luck because i really don't want to kill any of my passengers
myself included but you know i am i have my life insurance secured so hopefully everything's going
to be okay even if i do get killed at least my family uh will not uh remain poor all right we
are we're in the main menu so let's take at the main menu exit training charter flights business
flights scheduled flights free flights world map exploration profiles speaker test settings
add-ons about the program exit training as you can hear it's actually me voicing the menu for
now in the official english translation um because i'm the only one on the team who feels comfortable
enough at english to to actually do it and it's a pretty weird thing by the way to be hearing my
own i'm the only one on the team who feels comfortable enough at english to to actually do it and it's a pretty weird thing by the way to be hearing my own
voice as i'm talking to you at the same time but let's we'll not be spending much time in the main
menu today because we are to fly finally so let me let's let's make a flight from uh the london
heathrow airport in england or great britain to manchester also in england it's about 240
something kilometers long so it's going to take a while and it's hopefully going to give me enough
time to explain everything properly you know in enough detail as we go um by the way i'm sorry
to those of you who live in the us and are used to the imperial measurement units you know like
miles and feet and gallons etc because i really can't use them for for the life of mine
sorry about that i've honestly tried to make the game hopefully more approachable to you
but i can't make any sense of them honestly and they're really confusing me because
i'm not used to them at all but at the same time you can never please everyone at the same time
there are certainly going to be many listeners perhaps maybe even more of them than uh those
of you who are in the us and many listeners from europe who are used to
um to the um metric units so no matter what i do there's always going to be someone who is
not really happy i i guess but i believe it's not going to be too much of a problem
because you will be able to uh just set your game your personal copy of the game the way
you like it and use whichever measurement units you like when you start playing
charter business sketch free flights so i'll be doing a free flight
free flight dialogue my planes combo box one collapsed but i'm actually going to have to rent
the the plane that i'm going to use because we'll be flying with the boeing 787 dreamliner
which is a plane that i'm not actually qualified for yet in the game uh it's not part of my own
personal fleet yet so i'm going to have to filter edit company planes combo box one filter edit
rental offer combo box england badminton use the rental or service that i can use as a as a pilot
for the eurofly company now in version three uh when doing this uh when trying to rent a plane
the first thing i have to do is choose the starting airport actually so where we'll be
starting our flight where the plane will be placed before i actually take off with it
england doncaster so england london heathrow
uh england
heathrow plane rental dialogue you are about to rent an aircraft that's not part of your fleet
for a free flight your account will be charged zero do you wish to continue and no button alt
plus a yes i do wish to continue oh by the way i'm sorry uh the buttons any button yes and no
are uh displayed in check in my native language so that's why the screen reader reads them wrong
but it's not a bug in the game it's actually because my system language my local language
is set to check and i i forgot to to change it uh but i will not be editing
it
out just like i will not be editing anything out during the flight so if i uh make a mistake and
it causes me to stall or to crash because i was talking about something and i forgot to do
something vital in the meantime or forgot to do or couldn't do it in time well let's let's keep it
authentic i just will not be editing anything out uh and that's why um i will not be charged
anything i will be charged zero for this rental because i will not be charging anything i will be
using what i have so similar to the use case one because i'm using a tester
only you know private beta version of the game plane selection dialogue select concord boeing
787 dreamliner so let's select the 787 dreamliner and if i press enter now europe wielding controls
ready europe uk greater london hillingden harman's operate link we are airport london heathrow at the
uh heathrow airport sitting in the cockpit of our plane and we're ready to to get going now we have a
uh heathrow airport sitting in the cockpit of our plane and we're ready to to get going so let's keep
ready to to get going but before i do anything else let me show you the properties of the plane
which have also been greatly expanded and changed in version 3. and in that way it'll allow us to
see what kind of a beast we're actually even flying combo box pilot lucas hospital one
collapsed so i've opened them with the control enter keystroke and the very first line tells
me my name and my uh career level which is one for the time being so i'm actually still in training
that's why i don't have the qualification for the 787 to be able to fly it uh like uh in of my own
fleet skfre 696 free flight that's our call sign that will be used that the towers the controls
will use when uh contacting us over the radio to to refer to us and uh we can hear that it's a free
flight
boeing 787 dreamliner this is the name of the plane obviously transport plane jet plane three
rented it's a transport plane so it's not not it's not like a military plane it's a jet plane
that's talking about its propulsion it's category three meaning the largest possible uh type of
plane and it's currently rented so it's not my own certified one more reason for me to be really
careful because i don't want to smash it into the ground certified that means that
it's a plane which is a part of the official company fleet of eurofly and all pilots are
eligible to to use it for flights and to be ranked pushback required because this is a
large plane this is one of the new systems the first one it requires pushback meaning
planes cannot actually travel in reverse on their own uh not to mention such large planes so if i if i
drive into the gate for instance to pick up my passengers and i either need to get out of the gate
and continue going to my takeoff runway that i've been assigned by the tower i can't do that on my
own uh using the power of my own engines so the airport has i have to call the tower and ask them
to push me back to to send me the pushback tractor which is going to take me to the
to do it that's why i need to have when i'm flying such a large plane i also need to have
a large enough airport in this case it means i need an airport of category 3 for a plane of
category 3 also with the maintenance services like this like pushback to be able to take off
there and to be able to move on the airport with this plane condition 100 condition 100
this is another new feature in version 2 you may have been used to planes always being you know
in top shape and perfect working order and that that's not that's not no longer going to be the
case here um planes can get uh or various systems of the plane can get broken if we crash or if we
but it has to be just a minor crash while moving on the ground slowly and like crashing into a
building so we can break our
our lights or our onboard computer or other systems and then we'll need to ask the tower
for repairs uh but it can also happen just as the planes age and wear down over time you know so
last system check none the next line tells us that we haven't performed the system check uh
not even once yet number of c but if we have uh had done it which i'm going to do now i'm
going to leave the close the properties dialog with escape dashboard window and i'm going to
press ctrl shift uh z on the english keyboard yeah to perform the check starting system check
and if i now open the properties again certified condition 100 less system check just now just now
system check all systems are working correctly and we see that all systems are working correctly
number of seats 289.
essentially the tech spec sheet for the plane obviously it's going to be different for each
plane so we have a 289 seat number of passengers zero total obviously we don't have any passengers
on board at the moment wingspan 60m length 62m where is 62 meters long wingspan 60m oh so this
is actually quite interesting and i've never noticed it before but our wingspan is uh just
almost almost as much only two meters uh fewer
than the length of the plane 60 base weight 200t the base weight is 200 tons which is quite a lot
current weight 200 comma zero t and since we don't have any fuel as we've as we'll find out shortly
and no passengers either our current weight is still the same as the base weight but obviously
it can change with depending on how much fuel we load or how many passengers we board cruising
speed 955 kilometers this is the maximum declared uh
speed at which we'll be able to fly maximum cruising range 15 750 kilometers if we had our
full fuel tank completely full this is how far we would be able to travel in one flight uh uh in one
go uh at the most maximum cruising altitude 13 100 m so we can't fly any higher than a 13 100 meters
above the ground to to be safe and to avoid any damage of the engines flat positions zero slash six
and this is another new feature in version three flat positions
um you you heard that it's at zero slash six meaning they're currently set to zero out of six
possible um positions or uh levels and we can either erase the flaps upwards which is used
uh for taking off or downwards which is obviously used for landing so the planes the flaps are there
airborne even at low speeds uh in any case but the difference is obviously that if the play if the
flaps are raised upwards um it helps us to uh get up get out get away from the ground and lift uh
raise our nose and if it if they're um set downwards for landing it helps us to break faster
after landing base takeoff speed 260 kilometers base landing speed 260 kilometers
180 kilometers current stall speed 380 kilometers we really have to watch these speeds especially
all the current ones very carefully all the time during flight or until we get to know the plane by
heart and we're really confident about all its parameters because the base takeoff and landing
speeds again will be different depending on how much fuel and how many passengers we have
and the same um the basic the base stall speed is always the same but it says current
because the stall speed changes uh depending on the flaps that i was talking about before
so current takeoff speed 260 kilometers currently with an empty tank and with an empty cabin with no
passengers we would be able to theoretically be able to take off at 260 kilometers per hour
take off nose angle 6 to 11 17. minimum flap position while taking off two but we would have
to set the flaps upwards to position two for that at least two we could uh set them even
higher but the minimum required for a successful takeoff is two take off nose angle six to eleven
seventeen and we would have to raise the nose uh to an angle between six uh which is the minimum
the optimal angle is eleven and the maximum is seventeen for a successful takeoff if we raised
the nose higher than 17 degrees we would actually lose lift and stall minimum takeoff runway length
we also need a runway which is at least 2 700 meters long in order to be able to be able to
take off successfully to um gain enough speed for uh takeoff current landing speed 260 kilometers
and the current landing speed is also 260 kilometers um we can't land uh at a higher speed
than that if we land at a higher speed than that we can't land at a higher speed than that if we
were much higher speed by like more than 20 kilometers higher than that if we tried it
we would actually crash a crash and break on the ground on on contact with the ground minimum flap
position while landing four in order to be able to land successfully we have to have the flaps
set to four downwards minimum landing runway length one thousand eight hundred and seventy m
and the minimum landing runway length is actually shorter almost by a thousand meters shorter than
uh the minimum required runway length for takeoff because uh we will be having the flaps set to a
higher position for landing then we'll need to have them set for takeoff which means our
the length of runway that we're going to be able to break is going to be shorter for landing
but we need to keep watching the stealth the stall speed if you remember it said that our current
speed was 380 kilometers meaning we would actually stall and fall down to the ground much sooner
than we would be able to reach the required landing speed and that's why another reason
we need to use the flaps because when we retract them beyond zero in either direction the stall
speed um decreases because we're able to uh they're able to keep us airborne even at lower speeds
so the current stall speed of 380 kilometers would drop below the current takeoff or landing speed of
260 kilometers which is required fuel tank capacity 56 700 l current fuel load zero l currently we
don't have any fuel loaded current cruising range zero kilometers so we can't travel any distance
fuel used zero l haven't used any fuel yet either obviously battery off the battery is off the power
so another new feature in version 3 we can't actually do anything at all not even start
start the onboard computer or our radio or our transponder or any of the flights until we turn
on the battery or the power supply which which then provides the necessary power required to
start all the other systems including the engine off oh apu is another auxiliary power unit which
uh the larger planes have but the smaller ones don't the planes that have it need
to have the battery running as well in order to be able to start it because
we can't start any other systems including the apu including the engines without the
battery running but only if we have the battery running we can start the apu
which is already using our fuel supply a tiny bit and that's the system which
provides even more power than the battery, allowing us on these large Category 3 planes
to then finally start the engines, only once the APU is running.
We can see that both engines are off.
This is talking about gears and we'll be talking about this in a much greater detail in the
upcoming series of audio tutorials on Eurofly 3, which the basic series includes 15 recordings
describing various aspects of the program and then there is an upcoming, more advanced
series that describes how to actually fly and control in even more detail all the nine
basic planes that are required to successfully go
to Europe.
But very briefly, the gears are talking about the power of our engines, how much power,
how much output they're currently producing and thus how much speed will be moving, but
they're not directly related.
In Eurofly 3, any speed or any movement...
You don't just press a key anymore and that sets your speed, but any speed or course
changes are only the result of moving of your engine power, of the engine output, or in
the case of turning or climbing or descending, the result of how steeply you bank your wings
or your wheels.
Think of it like a steering wheel in a car.
Which...
If you wanted to turn, for example, to the left, you would...
You wouldn't just tap the wheel, you know, just press an arrow key.
You would need to keep holding it under a certain angle in the direction that you wish
to turn for a while.
As long as you wanted to keep turning, you would need to keep holding it.
So if you wanted to turn, say, 90 degrees to the left, you would need to keep holding
it, pointing or turning to the left for a while and only after you've turned as much
as you wanted.
If you are now satisfied with your current direction of travel, you could let go of the
wheel and keep going straight from that point on.
And the engine works pretty much the same.
You are moving a lever, essentially.
The result of the...
Or how much power the engines will be running on depends on how far or how high up you've
moved the lever.
Which obviously can be moved between...
Um...
Zero and one hundred percent.
One hundred is full power, zero is nothing at all.
But even if you set it to one hundred, it'll take the engines a while to actually reach
that full power.
You know, to accelerate.
Not to mention there's two modes of flight.
There's actual flight mode, but there's also the taxi mode for large planes like this one,
which are capable of the...
Of maximum speed.
Maximum cruising speeds above five hundred kilometers per hour.
And the taxi mode is used with these planes while moving along the airport.
Because we don't want to set the engine power to full...
Um...
Yeah, the engines to full power and start going like a hundred or two hundred and more
kilometers per hour while on the ground, while on the airport.
So if we turn on taxi mode, that will actually make the...
The lever...
Just the power lever adjustments much more fine.
So that even if we set the power lever to a hundred in taxi mode, it will actually only
be...
Um...
The resulting power will only be ten percent of the maximum available possible power of
the engines.
So only a tenth of the engine's maximum power.
Of the...
Um...
Possible one hundred.
Uh...
And in order to get the full power out of the engines, we would need to switch back
to flight mode.
So as soon as we're about to take off, we'll be switching from taxi mode to flight mode.
And the gears...
You don't have to press home or end a hundred times to, uh...
You know, move the lever all the way from zero to one hundred.
There are keystrokes either to set maximum power for the given mode or minimum power,
with a single keystroke.
Or there is another set of keystrokes to quickly move the power by ten percent, up or down.
Or there's a third set of keystrokes, which allows you to set the...
The specific gear.
Pretty much like shifting gears up or down in a car.
And the...
These plane properties here, this sheet, uh...
Tells us exactly...
What...
What percentage of the maximum possible power we'll be able to reach, and on any one of
these gears.
Engine.
Engine one.
Off.
Engine.
Gear one.
Zero comma one percent.
Two comma four percent.
Gear two.
Two comma five percent.
Four comma nine percent.
Gear three.
Five percent.
Seven comma four percent.
Gear four.
Seven comma five percent.
Nine comma nine percent.
Gear five.
Ten percent.
So, uh...
As you could hear, gear, uh...
One...
Gear one.
Engine two.
Started at, like, zero point something percent.
And ends at...
Engine.
Gear one.
Zero comma one percent.
Two comma four percent.
Two point four percent, which is barely enough to even start moving.
And gear five actually does not end all the way at one hundred, but it only goes up to
ten.
And that's exactly because of the taxi mode.
Once I switch to flight mode, the gear...
The percentages that we're able...
The power...
The percentages of the maximum power that we'll be able to reach for each gear will
change.
And, uh...
Gear five will let us go all the way up to one hundred.
But, by the way, it's never healthy and advisable to fly, uh, with the very full power with
one hundred.
For any engine.
Uh, so if we want to avoid, uh, engine damage, we should only be flying at ninety percent
of the time.
So, uh...
Uh...
you don't only need to use you don't only have in you you have more options than just using the
the ground brake after landing but you can also engage the reverse thrust to brake even faster
using the power of the engine but in that case remember that if you want to brake harder you
would actually have to increase the power in reverse thrust mode because the power of the
engine is going backwards but you still need more power to brake harder if that makes sense doors
closed cockpit open yeah our doors closed the cabin doors but our cockpit is open seat belt
unfastened we haven't even fastened our seat belt yet parking brakes active parking brakes uh i
think there are they are also a new system
as long as they're engaged we cannot move and this is a safety feature to make sure you don't
like drift along the runway while you're not yet ready to do so you're you're uh creating your
flight plan or boarding passengers or something landing gear you don't want to move you don't
want to move uh on your own or the plane to move by itself landing gear the landing gear is lowered
which means it's okay because and it has to be obviously when we're standing parked in the in
the hangar
uh so we're it we're ready for takeoff or for landing we've landed before so we're we're now
sitting on our wheels current flap position zero yeah the current flap position is zero we haven't
used them yet onboard computer off radio off these are the individual systems transponder off
communicator off of the plane which all of which are still off atlas off sensor off status monitor
off because we don't even have any power taxi lights off yet to turn them on cabin lights off
the lights strobe lights off
are a new thing in version three as well uh cabin taxi lights off these we need to have uh turned on
when we're taxiing on the airport so that the ground personnel and other taxiing planes can
see us cabin lights off these are the lights for the passengers so that they don't have to
uh spend all the duration of the flight sitting uh in their seats in the dark strobe lights off
strobe lights uh these are uh these make the plane visible visible from the outside
also to ground personnel but also in the air and to like passengers who are who are about to board it
and they're coming over to the gate or stand where we're sitting waiting for them so that they can see
which plane it is landing lights off and these are only used when we're about to land and slow
down and descend to reach the take the landing runway ventilation off ventilation cabin
pressurization off and cabin press pressurization off ventilation off and cabin pressurization off
are two new systems which also have to be on at all times during the flight which
take care of producing enough oxygens for the passengers not to suffocate in a higher altitude
temperature control off temperature control takes care of the weather obviously
so that the passengers don't like freeze or overheat during the flight storm radar off storm
when on can warn us of incoming or nearby storms tk off tcas is the system that warns planes that
are headed on uh perpendicular courses and are about to crash into each other so usually the
the tcas of one plane orders the pilot to climb while the system of the other plane orders their
pilot to descend
off to avoid the crash stall indication is another warning system that will warn us if our cruising
speed drops dangerously low and we've actually reached the stall speed the current stall speed
of the plane depending on the position of the flaps and we're just we're losing lift and we're
losing altitude gpws off gpws i believe it stands for ground proximity warning system and it's that's
what it does because in Eurofly 3 we also have to keep track and pay attention to yet another thing
and that is the terrain the elevation of the terrain in front of us because you know the map
well the map on a map on paper would be but the actual real world terrain is not flat
it's actually 3d so there are hills and mountains and ridges and valleys and all of that
cause the elevation or the height above sea level of the terrain below us to keep changing
to keep going up and down as we fly so we need to keep track of the of whether there's any hill
or mountain or any obstacle ahead of us with a higher with a greater height above sea level than
what our current altitude is and if there is we need to climb higher to avoid to avoid crashing
into it.
And the larger planes like this one have the system which warns us about this by itself
so it tells us to climb to avoid collision with the ground or to change course but on a smaller
simpler planes of category one without these automated systems we have to keep track of all that manually.
Bank angle indication on.
Bank angle indication is an audio cue that plays all the time when we're turning so
as I was saying before when our wings or wheels are banked to an angle causing us to to turn to change course so that we know we know we're actually turning we're not level we're not going straight.
Bank angle indication is an audio cue that plays all the time when we're turning so that we know we're not level we're not going straight.
And that this also is true this is also true for the nose if our nose is not straight we're also hearing this indication.
Audio navigation off.
Audio navigation I believe this is familiar.
We can have this on during flight to keep hearing.
A continuous tone at all times from the direction of our destination so that we can tell even by sound alone in which direction to go and where to turn in order to to be flying straight towards our destination.
Auto navigation off.
Auto navigation that's essentially the autopilot or all of these remaining systems are part of the autopilot which.
This one makes sure if enabled that the plane will always change.
Its course by itself to keep flying straight towards the destination at all times.
Auto speed inactive.
Auto speed we can.
Set the plane to speed up or slow down to any required speed that we want.
Auto course inactive.
Auto course we don't have to use the auto navigation to the destination that we have set before but we can also set the plane to go.
In any specific course that we desire which may not have to be the destination.
I'll show you this feature in.
In practice and how useful it is when I'm about to land auto altitude inactive in auto altitude we can also obviously excuse me set the altitude and we want to be flying in.
Okay.
These are the dashboard properties but we need to get moving don't we so let's let's actually start doing something.
Let me turn on the battery first.
Control shift B.
Because as I as I was saying before.
Without.
The battery I wouldn't even be able to turn on the onboard computer or any other systems.
Now let me turn on the.
Computer control shift K computer on warning fuel warning and we are hearing that we are out of fuel warning computer off so let me turn it off.
Just for now because that warning that looping warning is kind of annoying.
And let me fix that with smaller planes you can just you as the pilot can just just.
Poor.
Or the required amount of fuel in yourself.
But for larger planes like this we need to use the radio for this and we need to contact the tower and ask them to dispatch the refueler for us.
So let me turn on the radio control shift F radio on.
And let me find out the frequencies of all the possible towers or controls in range that I'm currently able to connect to.
We use the.
The.
Key nine on the numbers row for that combo box London Heathrow ground control one eighteen comma five collapsed and we can hear that there is a ground control London Heathrow approach control one thirteen comma eight and approach control the ground control obviously controls the planes that are taxiing along the airport while the approach control is for planes that are flying towards the airport and are about to land on it as well as for planes.
Once you've been assigned.
The runway to take off from and you're about to enter that runway.
That's when you switch your frequency from ground control to approach control and start talking to them and get the permission to enter the runway and then to take off from approach.
But for now let's London Heathrow ground control one eighteen comma five.
Let's dashboard window talk to ground control set frequency set frequency and we have to set frequency one one three point.
Five I believe it was one thirteen.
Comma five dashboard window set for one one three point six blank one thirteen comma six dash one thirteen comma six.
What was the combo box London Heathrow ground control one eighteen comma five collapse all white one eighteen point five my bad sorry one one eight point five London.
Ski for ground control dashboard six welcome to our airport.
The tower has welcomed us as we can hear well in my voice again but never mind.
No no other English towers yet.
That will be.
Up to you to change that.
In version three the towers are no longer static we actually talk to them we have to ask various permissions from them depending on what we're currently doing.
In our flight.
And you always do that by pressing F one combo box board asking for boarding collapsed and here you can see a list of all the possible requests that you can.
Make.
To the tower at the moment so.
For instance wouldn't make any sense to ask the ground control for landing clearance when we're not even in air not even flying.
So that's why you can't see that request here but you will see it in here in the list when flying and when.
Tuned to the approach frequency engines asking for permission to start the engines fuel asking for fuel gate asking for date assignment plan I want to create a flight plan push I need pushback repair I need repairs.
Runway asking for runway assignment on board asking for onboarding.
If I.
Tried to ask for onboarding for example at the moment you know I don't even have a flight plan created I don't I don't have any passengers on board.
At anything so the tower is context sensitive and smart so it won't let me do an obvious nonsense like that.
Dashboard window six nine six we haven't received any flight plan from you.
Now I'm about to fix that shortly.
Thank you but first combo give me some fuel fuel asking for fuel set fuel amount at a blank.
Two thousand.
Let me do two thousand liters I don't know how much that would be in gallons but that's going to be.
More than enough for us to make that whole flight successfully.
Two thousand.
Yes.
Six nine six we've dispatched the refueler for you.
Before the refueler arrives.
Let us do some more.
Things.
Some more.
Preparations.
From the checklist ahead of time.
So let's fasten our seat belt with control B.
Seat belt fastened.
We have already performed the system check but let's also turn on the systems that we can at the moment even without the APU and without the engines running.
Just the just those ones that we have enough power for even on battery alone.
So storm radar control shift s storm radar on strobe lights the outside lights shift.
S cabin lights on cabin lights sorry strobe lights are shift D strobe lights on taxi lights will also be needing them shift K taxi lights on let's turn on the transponder which will use shortly with control shift T transponder on.
And we can also turn on the atlas control shift L atlas on and communicator control shift G communicator on and the refuelers come so we can already start.
The turn on the onboard computer as well with control shift K computer on this time for good.
Because we will not be needing to turn it off anymore.
We won't be hearing the annoying warning anymore.
And now that everything's been done and we've been refueled.
Let's check out.
Check out our fuel load with E 2000 L.
Exactly as we requested.
So let's turn on the APU now with control page up.
And that's good.
That's going to give us enough power when it starts up finally to to turn on the engines.
By the way the atlas is just another panel.
If you have it turned on you can move with the tab key.
So you don't only have to be on the dashboard controlling the plane but you can press tab navigation atlas window to get to the atlas window and you can use the keystrokes that you would otherwise use in the manual world map exploration mode.
So as you're flying without needing to leave your plane you can check anything that you need to on the atlas communicator channel 0 and the communicator box collapsed would let you chat to or send audio messages voice messages to other pilots to other actual real life players that are currently online and connected to the server and playing Eurofly alongside you dashboard window the APU is on.
So let's turn on the other systems that we'll be needing for.
For the flight that I was talking about.
Let's do TCAS on TCAS with control shift C stall indication stall indication control shift E temperature control control shift you temperature control on ventilation control shift ventilation on cabin pressurization control shift P cabin pressurization WS the one which warns us not to crash into the ground control shift.
W GP WS on and let's also turn on the sensor with control backspace sensor on I forgot to mention that before that's another new system where if you're moving on a taxiway or runway it it'll indicate audibly that there's an obstacle ahead of you or off to the side or that you're about to leave the runway.
Let's ask the tower.
Let's ask the tower for permission to start our engines because with large planes like this one you can't just turn on the engines anytime you want because they produce a lot of noise and a lot of airflow and you wouldn't want to say knock a random innocent ground control personnel away or something so let's ask for the permission engines asking for permission to start the engines dashboard window six nine six you have permission to start the engines.
Thank you.
Start engines.
Engine one with page up starting engine two with page down starting and you can hear that each of them is playing from a different place in the stereo field engine one is on the left engine two is on the right since it takes a lot of time for the engines to actually start up but this is something seasoned players of your flight to will have known will be told with a voice prompt as well as soon as the engines are done actually starting up.
Let's find out where we're located West S course we're facing West minus 500 hangar two we're in the hangar two with the K 300 hangar two and L keys these two tell us our coordinates on the airport K says announces the north south coordinate so from bottom to top if you were to take at the entire airport as a flat surface as a flat area as though yeah on a painted on a sheet of paper.
The.
Lowest number of the first number would be.
All the way down to the south in the in the lower corner and the higher numbers would be all the way up in the upper part or upper on the upper edge minus 500 hangar two so it since it says minus 500.
We can tell that we are at the very south edge of the airport and the L key does the same but for.
The.
West east or left to right coordinate so the higher the number the farther off to the right we are on the map or in the area of the airport 300 hangar two 300 that's also pretty.
Far to the west or to the left because the maximum coordinate would be like 200 2600 or 3000 or something and since we are we know we are in the hangar which we can also.
Verify with the okey hangar doors closed west.
It says that the hangar doors are closed so let's open it with shift o.
So that we don't you know so that so that we don't crash into the doors as we try to pick up some speed and drive off the hangar.
Let's also find our doors are high above sea level while we're at it.
That's done.
Okay.
That's done with the semi colon key 16.
So this airport is actually only 16 meters above sea level or above.
Yeah.
Above sea level.
Airport London Heathrow.
Yeah.
We can find out with F 118 comma 5 London Heathrow ground control our frequency and it says that we're properly connected to the London Heathrow ground control.
So we should be ready our engines are running.
Let's.
Disengage the parking brakes with B so that we can actually start moving.
Parking brakes off.
Let's ask the tower to assign us a gate or stand to taxi to where we'll be picking up our passengers.
Combo gate asking for gate assignment dashboard 696.
We haven't received any flight plan from you and I have completely forgotten to create my flight plan.
My bad.
I was saying before that I'm about to fix it.
Well let's do that now.
First I'm going to pick my destination where I want to fly because I believe that's the faster and easier way to do it.
So let's display the list of all the available airports.
There are several different ways.
You may know them from previous versions but I'm in this case I'm going to use the list ordered by distance from closest to farthest.
So I'm going to press control F 8.
Combo box England London.
England France.
Let's choose England Manchester and let's add it as our destination.
Add destination to navigation with space.
Let's leave this dialog and let's now ask the tower with F1 to create a flight plan.
We can see our call sign here but you can see that this is a read only edit field so we can't change the call sign at any time during the flight.
And since I just chose the destination before and added it to my navigation it's already pre-filled in here for us.
So another press of the tab key.
There's the filter if I wanted to if I didn't hadn't done this before and I now had to choose my destination manually and there would be like thousands of airports.
I could filter or narrow my search down here using the filter field.
Flight description edit blank.
There's a flight description field where other players could see like what this flight is actually about.
If they were checking the other players that are currently there.
So let's put in something here.
Sounds good to me.
Asking for a navigated flight.
That would be a flight corridor that the tower would create for us.
For long distance flights like this one.
Planes don't usually fly in a straight line directly to their destination.
But they're flying over designated flyover points.
But I'm actually going to ask for a direct flight this time.
Direct flight.
We could also do.
Flight corridor through my waypoints.
So not a flight corridor that the control tower would determine for us.
But rather let's say that I wanted to fly to Manchester then to Birmingham and then back to Heathrow.
All in one flight.
So what I could do is I could put all these three destinations into my navigation.
Excuse me.
In the order that I want to fly through them.
And if I then chose this option.
Flight corridor through my waypoints.
When creating my flight plan.
That's what the flight corridor would be.
Direct flight.
But let's ask for direct flight.
Another press of tab.
My waypoints combo box Manchester collapsed.
My waypoints only include Manchester the destination for now.
So that's in order.
Passengers checkbox not checked.
And there's the checkbox for passengers.
Yes I do want to have passengers.
So I'm going to check it.
Ask for flight button.
And there's the ask for flight button.
Dashboard window.
SK696.
Flight plan accepted.
Set transponder.
To 1517.
Our flight plan has been accepted.
We're supposed to set the transponder now.
I can either repeat.
If I forget.
I can either repeat the last tower announcement with space.
SK696.
At any time.
Flight plan accepted.
Set transponder.
To 1517.
Or I can also press.
In this case.
I can also just press shift T.
For transponder.
To hear just the value that's been assigned to us.
1517.
SKFRE 696 London.
Manchester.
So.
It's 1517.
1517.
Yes.
So let's press alt T to set the code.
Set transponder value.
Set.
1517.
Dashboard window.
Now the tower should finally allow us to start our engines.
Engines.
Asking for permission to start the engines.
Dashboard window.
SK696.
You have permission to start the engines.
Oh wait.
But they're already.
They're already running right?
Engine 1.
0.
Engine 2.
That's just the APU.
Okay.
So.
Stopping.
Oh no.
They were running.
I'm stupid.
Zero means.
Yeah.
The power.
They were not.
Um.
Producing any output.
Any thrust.
So that's why.
Done.
That's why.
They were at zero.
So again.
But we did get the permission though.
Never mind.
We got it a second time even.
So let's just restart them again.
Starting.
I have a flight plan.
And couldn't do because I didn't have any plan.
So I just remembered now.
Was actually to ask for the gate or stand to pick up passengers.
Combo.
Gate.
Asking.
Dashboard window.
SSK 696.
Taxi to stand 5.
The difference between a gate or stand is that the stand is like a drive through.
You can drive through it in any direction.
And.
and stop there and if you if you've entered the stand say coming from the
south so facing north you could then keep going on in the same direction keep
going north and drive through it and leave it at the other side where is a
gate is an extension for of the actual airport building so that's why you have
to use a push back to get out of a gate you can't just keep going straight
because you would then crash into the airport building okay so we're supposed
to taxi to stand one so we can start moving we are now in the hangar minus
500 hangar to 300 hangar to hangar doors open West we the doors are open so I
believe we're ready we've done everything so I'm going to press alt home
to set the engine power to the maximum
but remember it's only going to be 10% of the overall engine power because we
are currently in taxi mode gear 5 gear 5 3 keep checking my six print speed with
our 12 14 once it gets it to 17 19 20 I'm going to choke it with control
delete 21 fix it so that it doesn't 21 like doesn't drop any further 200 and
750 we're now on the mic 304 tax on the mic
which is 338 349 which goes from zero seven seven seven seven six five five
four three three from the hangars one one zero north from the hangars and we
were we left the hangar facing west but this is a so north-south taxiway so we
had to turn 90 degrees to the right to be facing north now and keep driving a
long mic facing north and it'll lead us to the turning which leads to the taxiway
called Zulu and this is the one that leads to north to the stands so we'll be
facing uh East I believe
we can bank the wheels with by up to 50 degrees so that means how sharply we'll
be turning and you do that with either left or right obviously
or with shift left and shift right arrow key for 10 degrees of the wheel
inclination for with each press so I just pressed shift right five times to
bank the wheels by 50 degrees and I'm listening to this one this sound tells
me each 10 degrees that I've turned so 80 90. press G key quickly to level my twice quickly to level my
a taxi to stand five to level my plane 23.
set flat position six dashboard window I'm actually supposed to it helps to
extend the flaps down even when I'm just going difficult songs because that helps
to break faster so that's what I'm doing so we're just traveling East along Zulu we can hear the
stand one turning
left and I'll slow down to 10 once we are driving by stand 4 so that I then
have enough time and enough room to turn sharply to the west to the north to turn
sharply by 90 degrees then to be facing stand 5 again the layout of the airport
is something that you can read and learn in the airport descriptions airport
properties with shift enter and what I'll be demonstrating in a bit when we
are flying stand 4 so I'm slowing down alt end to 21 flaps extended
downwards to 6 set the engines to 0 19 flaps extended downwards watching my
speed with R 17 flaps extended downwards to 6 to choke it off again with control
delete once it reaches 10 14 flaps extend 13 flaps extend 13 flaps extend 12 flaps extend 12
11 11 11 11 10 flaps choked off gear 1 and once I start hearing the beacon now
I
force the and 5 let's just press shift 5 left many times and turn 90 degrees to
the left 20 30 and the other higher sharper sound that's the bank angle
indication so that tells us that we're actually turning right now stand 5 stand
5 here 0 6 4 3 3 2 1
breaking breaking breaking by holding down the slash key to stand still so I'm
now facing 359 ah 359 just one degree left over north but I'm standing still
zero flaps extended downwards to six in each stand 5 stand 5 5 stand 5 so that's
perfect almost a perfect stop considering the circumstances considering that I
have to be talking not while I'm abandoning both Taiwanese can Yes I can
So let's engage the parking brakes again, B.
Let's ask the tower to board the passengers.
And let's open the cabin doors for them with CTRL-R.
So that they can actually get in once they arrive, you know, once the bus brings them.
And once they bring the steps for them, so that they can climb up into the plane and so on.
Which obviously takes a while, so that's why we are not hearing anything yet.
So while we are sitting here waiting for them, that's why I engaged my parking brakes.
For safety reasons, so that we don't move even an inch.
So that the plane doesn't move even an inch on its own.
I could ask for the runway, but the tower wouldn't give me one.
For the take-off runway, but the tower wouldn't give me one until I have passengers on board.
And we can hear them coming now, finally.
We can hear their footsteps, their boarding, and sitting down and taking off their jackets and fastening their seatbelts.
Like proper responsible passengers, that's good, because you don't even know what's coming yet.
You have no idea who you're flying with.
You have no idea that your pilot is not qualified for this type of plane.
If you did, you would never dare board it.
But since you don't, your lives are in my hands.
Your death.
Your destiny.
And your fate is all in my hands.
Just stupid.
Okay, the last one is about to sit down.
245.
We have 245 people on board.
You can hear the sounds of other planes taxiing and taking off and landing around us.
Now we can hear the bustle and speech of the passengers.
Let's close the doors.
The outside doors, the cabin doors.
Closed.
We can also close our own cockpit with Alt-O, because this is annoyingly loud and I wanna be able to talk.
Let's disengage our parking brakes again.
Parking brakes off.
And now, finally, let's ask the tower to assign me the takeoff runway.
Combo runway. Asking for runway assignment.
Dashboard window.
SK696, you've been assigned runway 09 left.
You can taxi.
09 left.
You know what?
Maybe this is actually a good time.
This is a good time to show you the airport properties.
Just like the plane properties are accessible with Ctrl-Enter, the airport properties are accessible with Shift-Enter.
Combo box pilot Lucas Hosnittel, 1, collapsed.
SKFRE 696, free flight.
This reiterates the call sign of our flight and my career level.
The first official English demonstration of Eurofly 3 by Lucas.
This is the description that I filled out while creating the flight plan.
Boeing 787 Dreamliner, 3.
This is the flight, the plane type.
GLL, London, Heathrow.
This is the ICAL sign of the airport, which is actual real-world, real-life data.
This is the unique international identifier for each airport, which is obviously different for each.
Public with maintenance services, 3.
This is a category 3 airport.
It's a public one with maintenance services, so including pushback and the refuelers and stuff like that.
Height above sea level, 16m.
As we've already seen before, this is...
Located at just 16m above the sea level.
Difficulty, 1.
This refers to how difficult it is to land on this airport in relation to the surrounding terrain.
So if it's a difficulty 1 airport, that means that the surrounding terrain is relatively flat and shouldn't be too challenging to land on.
Ground control, 118,5.
There are the radio frequencies for ground control and approach control.
Approach control, 113,8.
And there's the airport description.
This is the interesting part.
And the new part.
Runways 2.
There are two runways here.
Runway 09R27L, 3,657m.
There's runway 09R27L, which is...
3,657m long.
The designation...
The numbers that designate the runways are interesting.
Since it's...
Since it's a 09 runway, it means that it goes from east to west, because 90 is due east.
You should actually always add one more zero to the end of the runway designation number.
So 09 would become 090, and 27 would become 270, so due west.
So it's...
It's the same...
The very same runway in both cases, but since it's an east-west one, the 27 runway is the
other end of the runway, actually.
So if you were approaching the airport from the other side, you would likely be assigned
the runway 27L to land on, and not 09R.
L and R obviously stand for left and right.
So that's why you have different entrances, different auxiliary taxiways to help you reach
the required entrance of your assigned runway, so that you don't...
For instance, if you're supposed to be using the runway 27, you don't want to be coming...
You don't want to enter it facing east, facing 09, and to go west along the runway, actually.
So in that case, you would be doing... Going north.
Going in the exact opposite direction than what the tower assigned you.
So we see that we enter the 09R runway from the delta taxiway, and we can even hear the
latitude and longitude coordinates here.
Of that entrance point.
So it's 550 south, 150 west.
And to get to the 27L entrance, so to the exact opposite end, we would need to be moving along Delta, then turn to the Sierra taxiway once that turning comes, then drive along Sierra, then turn to Yankee once that turning comes.
And only from the Yankee taxiway we would see the entrance to the runway 27L at coordinates 550 south, but 3380 or something east.
Yeah, the surface is asphalt of the runway.
Here's the same for the other runway, which is 09L 27L.
Runway 09L 27R, 3900 and 1M.
Which is maybe longer, if memory serves.
Runway 09R 27L, 3657M.
Yeah, it's like 300 meters longer.
Surface, runway 09L 27R.
So this airport has two runways with the exact same designations that are parallel.
They are literally next to each other as you travel along the main Delta taxiway.
First, because Delta is always the one that goes north.
South to north.
That means you would be driving along the 09R runway first, and then along 09L.
There are other taxiways like Sierra and Yankee and Foxtrot to help you get to the other end of the runway without going off the taxiway.
Entrance 09L, Delta, 850, 150.
Entrance 27R, Delta, Foxtrot, Yankee, 850, 4000, and 50.
You see that we would have to go north.
We would have to go from Delta to Sierra to Yankee to get to the runway 09L.
Whereas for 09R, it's Delta, then Foxtrot, then Yankee.
Surface, ASP, runway 09L, Entrance 09L, Delta, 850, Entrance 27R, Delta, Foxtrot, Yankee, 800.
Oh, yeah, I flipped them around, but I hope you understand.
Hangar 1, Alpha Mike.
To get to Hangar 1, you would have to use the Alpha taxiway, then turn to Mike, and then there would be the turning to Hangar 1.
And the same is true for Hangar 2.
Main area, southeast.
The main area, which is where we'll be driving along as soon as we leave the stand, the largest chunk of the airport where all the main taxiways are leading off, that's southeast.
Meaning, you know, at the bottom right part of the airport, and the hangars are thus left of it.
If this line said that the main area was located southwest, it would mean that the hangars are located to the right of the main area.
And thus, they would be situated in the southeast, like, corner or segment of the airport.
Number of gates, five.
It has five.
This airport has five gates.
Number of stands, five.
And also five stands.
Total area, 1,000.
450 x 4,150.
Yeah, this is the total area of the airport in meters.
Security zone 200.
There's also a security zone 200 meters wide in all directions around the airport.
So if we, like, left the runway or taxiway by accident, we would still have time to slow down or stop and turn around and get back to our designated runway.
Because there are also a new feature in version 3R.
Penalty.
Penalty points.
If we crash and destroy the plane or stall, obviously, that's a major accident, and we don't earn any money and any points in the global leaderboard.
But on the contrary, we even lose them, obviously, because we lost a plane.
But you can also get penalty points for minor infractions, like leaving the designated runway or starting the engines without permission.
Or entering the takeoff runway without permission, and so on.
And for, I believe, 20 accumulated penalty points, you lose a...
Or maybe for 10 accumulated penalty points, you lose a point from your earnings.
So it can actually move you down the leaderboard and decrease your overall score.
But you can check this out in detail in the rules document, which explains all these...
Details, all these principles that govern the behavior of Eurofly pilots.
And you can find these rules on the game's official website at eurofly.stafankiss.sk.
So these are the airport properties.
Have we been assigned a runway yet?
Oh, we are. We have.
O-line left.
That means...
That means we'll be having the farthest one...
The farthest one from...
From our current position that we can have.
Let's just fix our direction slightly.
And choke off our speed.
We're now in the main area.
I have to turn west.
To...
Get to the stands.
This is K696.
The passengers are already on board.
Oh, I don't need to.
I'm stupid.
0 to 257.
16 flaps extended downward.
116 main area.
I don't need to worry about passing by the stands.
I have already boarded them.
307.
0 to 100.
133 flaps.
Gear 4.
Gear 0.
Let me not talk for a while.
39 flaps extended.
35 flaps extended.
30...
Gear 0.
30 flaps extended.
29 flaps extended downwards to 6.
21 flaps extended downwards to 6.
14 flaps extended downwards to 6.
Gate 3.
Let me not...
Talk over this.
Gate 3.
I need to explain the main area.
Because the main area...
Gate 3.
The main area...
Is...
300 meters wide.
300 meters wide from south to north.
And you can essentially split it into like 3 lanes.
The bottom most one or the south most one between the K coordinates of 0 to 100.
That's where the stands are from west to east.
From left to right.
Along the length of the main area.
Gate 3.
The south to north coordinates between 100 and 200.
229 main area.
So we're already over this.
Gate 3.
Are where the main taxiways of the airport are.
That's where I'm trying to get.
Because to get to delta and then to my assigned runway 09 left, we need to go through alpha.
Gate 3.
Through the alpha taxiway.
And between the south, north coordinates of 200...
Gates 3.
200 and 300 on the main area in the main area there are the gates so we can now hear the
turning to gate three and let's hope i'm not going to crash into it
turn all the way away away from it six flaps seven flaps extent seven flaps i want nothing to have
uh nothing to do with it seven flaps 305 let me turn all the way west 298 i think i'm going to
make it 293 yeah i'm not going to drive into it because i 285 if i did 282 i would need to ask for
pushback 277 275 272 268 managed not to get into it to drive into it which is good 260 247 main area
246 main area let me turn even closer to or left of west 250 closer to south 247 in order to get
more southward on the main area 238 main area i'm now at coordinates 238 231 south to north which is
too far up too far north 229 main area i need to get to like 0 217 223 main area below 200 220 main
area 217
seven flaps extended 210 main area 206 main area zero 203 main area 201 main area 200
now let's turn to the right let's turn due west 213 and we'll reach the alpha taxiway 219
southwest because if an airplane has an alpha taxiway that's one of the three possible main
one 240 which always uh goes due west from the main area 251 if you're not not a plane but 150 airport
obviously 260 if the airport has a bravo taxiway that's the same principle one of the 171 270 west
170 main area okay this should let us enter alpha perfectly 439 main area we still have a long ways to go
we still have a long ways to go we just need to speed up a little bit since there
is a bravo here
20 flaps extended downwards to east and delta if there is one always goes due north these are the
main three possible taxiways and 334 main area um but since there
there are the gates to the northern main area
278.
Cabin lights off. Cabin lights on. 284. 200. 274. 268.
260. 262. 263. 200. Cabin lights off. Cabin lights on. 273. 200. 279. 278.
270. 270. 270. 270. 270. 270. 270. 200. 200. Okay. Delta.
Paused. Since there were the gates in the northern part of the main area, and I needed to get to
Delta, because I know that runways 09R and 09L lead from Delta, I needed to drive a bit
along Alpha first, so to go due west, to pass the gates on my right, to get around the gates
in the north, and only then, as you can see, as I was trying to align my direction, I was going
along Alpha, there was the turning to Mike on my left, which would lead me to the hangars, but
that's not where I wanted to go, so I kept going west, and now I'm about to turn due north to
travel along the main taxiway of Delta. Resumed. 20 flaps extended. 294. 304. Delta.
Delta. I'm already on Delta, but I need to fix my direction.
Zero. Two. Two. One. One. North. Zero. North. Now I'm going due north. 632m. 20 flaps extended
downwards to six. At a perfect speed along Delta.
So I think I'm pretty safe, and I'm about to stop at my designated take-off runway, which is 09L,
and we're finally about to take off. You can see that there's a lot to do even before
you can take off, and it's a complex process. There's the Sierra taxiway, which would help us
to get to... Sierra 27L, if we needed to use that. Sierra.
end of this upcoming 09R runway. Let me switch to the approach control though
because I know I'll be needing to talk to them now and to ask
them for permission to enter my runway and to take off. That's now no more in
the power of ground control so that's why. There was our 09R, we need to keep
going further and there is a foxtrot, another taxiway, which would
help us to get to the other end of that 09L taxiway. I'm slowing down to 10 so that I have enough time to turn to face due east then when the turning comes.
This should give us more than enough time hopefully and I'm going to ask the
tower to give me the permission to enter the runway. You know there might be another
plane there currently trying to take off from it or something so I can't just
turn and drive into the runway without permission but I'm permitted so that's
fine and here it comes already. So I'm turning right,
10 degrees, 20 degrees by the way. You can change obviously the interval and the
way it can be either sounds or words. You can configure this the way you like in the
program settings. I'm pressing S alongside the indication to make sure.
you have engines to zero power and hold down slash to brake. Okay we're standing
in place extended downwards to six. Parking breaks to make sure.
There's 3890 meters of runway left ahead of us. You can
find this out if you press the K key twice because K once gives you the latitude,
coordinate or south-north coordinate but pressed twice tells you how long the runway ahead of you
is and the same is for L which normally tells you the longitude but if you press it twice
you'll see that there's 11 meters of the runway behind us so I before I was able to fully brake
and fully stop I traveled only 11 meters of the runway length of the total runway length with
which is an excellent feat if I can say so myself minimum maximum maximum minimum flat
position minimum takeoff runway takeoff runway length is 2,700 meters and since we have 3,890
3,890 meters left we are more than good to go because that's over a thousand meters more than
a kilometer of runway length than we need it's always good to have
a research
when trying to take off now first thing first things first let's not forget to switch to
flight mode with shift delete flight mode or we wouldn't be able to take off at all and be
wondering like why am I no longer picking up any speed why am I stuck at the 10 powers 10%
of the engines power and at the speed of like 50 now let's set the flaps upwards
for takeoff because they're now set downwards for landing you can maximum cruising out to find out
in the plane properties maximum cruising minimum maximum minimum flat position while taking off two
that the minimum required flat position weight when taking off is two but I'm actually going
to set them to six six because I already know this plane and this route very well and I know
that it just helps to gain the required speed faster if I said if I extend it if I extend the
flight now let's ask for the clearance to take off combo takeoff asking for takeoff clearance
dashboard window six nine six cleared for takeoff we are cleared for takeoff which is good let's
press delete to find out the status of the engines just to make sure zero power zero percent gear zero
flight mode okay so what zero position zero power zero but in gear zero but in flight mode so that's
good R
zero flaps extended upwards to six now tells us that we're not moving our speed is zero but
the flaps are extended upwards to six everything's good we have takeoff clearance let's just check out
our current takeoff speed in the plane properties briefly you can just press control enter and keep
pressing C condition current weight cruising speed current stall speed current takeoff speed 279
kilometers 279 kilometers you see that we now that we've loaded fuel and uh boarded passengers
the base takeoff speed if memory serves was 260 kilometers per hour but it's nine now 19 kilometers
higher than that it's now 279 because we obviously got heavier so it's going to take more power and
more runway length to for us to get moving at speed dashboard window so let's get going let's
get in the air I'll press alt home to set the engines to gear five quickly or to the
90 of their maximum power which is actually also the maximum recommended power to be flying safely
oh I forgot to disengage the parking brakes you saw nothing happened B parking brakes off now alt
home gear six and I'll keep watching my speed with our two flaps Extended upwards to six
five flaps Extended upwards to six I can check out my power and my engine status with delete once more
sure. You see that the power is set to 90% and it's currently at 63. It's about to raise
to 90. Gear 6, flight mode. So the engines are fine. We're currently cruising at the
speed of 70. And we have still over 3,500 kilometers left ahead of us. So we're fine.
We're more than fine. 135. So I still need to speed up by another 140 kilometers in order
to be able to take off successfully. 179. Now 100 more kilometers of speed and I can
take off. I'm going due east. So everything's fine. 226. When I have reached 279, I'm going
to press shift down.
I can quickly raise the nose by 10 degrees because you can press down or up. But I don't
want to be tapping them 10 times. 5 more. My nose angle is now 150. You could hear the
GPWS system giving us the readouts of the altitude as it increased over 100 above ground.
And you could also hear, but it was probably drowned by the...
The GPWS voice that the takeoff has been successful. So I can put in the landing gear
with control G. 200. I can turn on auto navigation to the destination with alt. I was told to
climb to 7-1, to altitude 7-1. So alt-Y for that. 7-1-0.
This works just like the... I need to... Oh. Shift-F. Set flaps to 2. Lower the flaps
because my cruising speed is already high enough. And if I kept them all the way at 6, they
would be damaged. The altitude designations work exactly the same as the runways in that
you add one more zero to the end of the readout. So if the tower told us to climb to 7-1, that
actually means 710 meters. 7-1-0. 383. We're above the stall speed, above the base stall
speed.
So I can lower the flaps or retract the flaps all the way to zero. To not be using them
at all. And also to avoid them getting damaged.
440.
see that our speed keeps getting higher now it's 453 kilometers per hour we're still turning
to our destination this sound is the back angle indication and the
sound played every time we turned by 10 degrees now it's stopped so you can see if i check the
airport uh if i check my uh position uh in relation to my destination with the n
key for navigation it says dead ahead at 328 comma seven dead ahead at 328.7
if i check my course now 328 comma seven slash 228 comma seven auto it says auto at the end
meaning we are flying using auto navigation and if my if i check my altitude with uh
y 711
it's 711 well it's that's okay the tower asked us to climb to 710 so this is uh okay 601 the speed
is getting ever faster the declared cruising speed of this plane is 955 kilometers per hour
let me check the distance to the airport now 231 kilometers manchester 22 minutes that's still 231
kilometers away and it's going to take us 22 minutes to get there at our current speed but
since we're still gaining speed it's actually going to work
to be much faster one more thing that i wanted to show you is another new feature in eurofly
because as you can see already there's tons of different keystrokes and it's just not possible
for anyone i think to remember them at all uh to remember them all uh on the first go
you know off the top of your head so there's a help system there's an extensive interactive
help system built into eurofly you can turn that on or off at any time with alt h
for help so this is actually one essential keystroke that it's really good to remember
of age help mode on tree view there's a tree view here map 92 collapse you can see your arrow keys
there are several different categories of keystrokes and there's a lot of them engines
15 there's 15 keystrokes for engines and to try control category 11 on board computer 17 collapsed
in the meantime communicator one collapsed other opening 18 bovington the map is reading out the
playing edge easy to work with and can be addressed in a variety of ways and so it may not seem like
the only logical thing is to turn on the application once it's put on which means you're very much
on purpose unless you want to I put default there again in there and you can walk all the way to
see where it goes here and here and do exactly what you're going to do what you're going to let
it go if you want to you can turn it off once it's off and you can see well the play is down
2 which is close with the networkelf switch and then killing says year 10 here's where the peak
sounds in there and then over pret back here at the lower right here's the kickstand tip side
1 1 a little bit faster also in there and then you can control those but i'll see that it tends to move a little
away slightly to easier tablespoon both with concept control at the dirt and here's where charm as with not
some meaning by what it's supposed to do so let's say that I forgot how to turn
on and off the reverse thrust so I can just type in thrust here into the search
field tree view map 92 search edit thrust and I if I press tab once more
results combo box control plus page down reverse thrust on slash off collapsed
there's the results there's only one keystroke and that's that says that it's
control page down to turn the reverse thrust on or off and there's another
edit read only less not set greater another edit field where we can just
press the key keystroke and it tells us what it does so if I don't know what say
control shift enter does display all planes currently display all planes
currently at the airport what does space do repeat the last tower announcement
slash in a list or tree view of airports the last tower announcement or there's
another purpose of the same keystroke when
browsing
the map and so on so this is what you can do sound overview combo box
automatic operation completed collapse and there's a sound overview you can
browse the sounds with the arrow keys and play one with space so automatic
operation completed means if I was turning like I was before with auto
navigation enabled or I was climbing to the set auto altitude when I hear this
dong it means that the turning or the climb has been
been completed course changed by specified amount of course changed by
specified amount that's the that that place every time I turn by 10 degrees as
configured in my program settings bank angle of the wheels winged this is this
place regularly when we're turning or our nose is not level take off or
landing runway beneath the plane take off for landing runway beneath the
plane is a really important one this is a continuous tone so you cannot
stop it at any at any time by pressing space one more time
this will play when we're about to land and we're flying over the or above the designated runway
sensor warning one you are near the edge of the sensor warning so when we are near the edge of
the taxiway sensor warning two you this will get faster in speed as we get closer and we hear this
continuous tone we're at the very edge of the taxiway or runway taxiway or runway entrance
beacon you've heard this when i was turning to delta and then to o9l etc and you can also
press tab one more time and there's various tips which you can browse through with the arrow keys
telling you everything that you can do in this current mode currently we're flying so it tells
us anything we can do when flying perform the flight to your destination make use of the map
and look around you make use of the atlas in order to obtain more information control plus shift plus
that turns the atlas on and off communicate with other pilots control plus shift plus g
listen to the radio or background music alt plus y etc explore the properties of the destination
airport control plus f8 so that's the help feature i believe that's a pretty cool one dead ahead of
159 kilometers we still have 159 kilometers to go to manchester so i can show you one more
pretty cool thing and that's the the descent map of an airport which is really useful and
we need to check it out and we need to get familiar with that
before we attempt to land if we want to be successful so let's uh let me pull up manchester
again to see its properties combo boxing control at eight england east england london england london
england london england england manchester england manchester now that i've found it in the list
let's i'll press shift enter on it to uh display its properties combo box pilot uh we saw the
airport description but if i now press tab combo box descent map collapsed there's the another panel
that's the descent map height above sea level 71 f so manchester is 71 meters above sea level
whereas heathrow was 16 meters above sea level same altitude safe circle zero comma three k
same altitude safe circle 0.3 kilometers 300 meters in all directions around the airport
there are no hills um at the same altitude that means if i was trying to land if i was or fly
i was approaching the airport at an altitude of 500 and uh so there would not and i was 300 meters
away from the airport there would be no mountains or hills or terrain changes in either direction
but if i got farther away than 300 meters away from the airport there could be a mountain or a
hill on one side of the airport so that's why i have to pay attention to what the gpws is telling
me or i have to check the i have to look ahead manually if there's an obstacle or
with control semicolon dashboard window if there's an obstacle in migrant altitude not detected
when it says not detected it means i'm flying i can keep flying on course and i'm safe there's
no hill or mountain in my current direction in my current altitude dead ahead 125 kilometers
two kilometers five kilometers same altitude safe circle zero comma three and now it tells me
you know when i'm two kilometers away from the airport two kilometers safe altitude 142 m which
is 43 m above ground i can climb to altitude a descent to altitude 143 meters which is
43 meters above ground and you'll see as we're getting farther away from the airport
like this circle around the airport increases from two kilometers this time to five kilometers
five kilometers safe altitude 144 m which is the same the safe altitude uh also increases
so we have to climb or to descend gradually as we approach the airport 10 kilometers safe altitude
165 m which is 66 m above ground 15 kilometers safe altitude 177 m which is 78 m above ground to a
20 kilometers safe altitude 225 m which is 126 m above ground and and so on and so on all the way
up to 100 kilometers but if you're already flying on if you've already been assigned the runway to
land and you're flying on course you're aligned with the runway already you can actually descend
much lower and much earlier than that because now you know which side you're approaching the airport
from and you don't need to worry about possible like mountains on the other side of the airport
so that's why there is a runway 5 12 27 runway 33 0 dashboard window uh wait combo i chose the
wrong england manchester wrong airport combo combo runway zero five r ah this is manchester yeah
runway zero five r if we're out aligned with runway zero five r and we're approaching it
zero comma six km descend to 89 m which is 18 years 30 and we are 33 kilometers away from it we can
descend to altitude 180 meters
meters which is 35 kilometers descent to 108 m which is 37 37 meters above ground then when we
are at zero comma six km 600 meters away from the airport we can descend to 89 which is 89 meters
which is 18 meters above ground so that's uh useful to know when we are when you're already about to
um hit the runway to land on the runway but as i said i know this route well so i i remember these
values
values already i don't need to look them up anymore but even if i do there's a few more
useful keystrokes to do that with by pressing 8 on the number zero at any time i can find out
what airport is currently the closest to me or which airport's controlled area i'm currently
flying over controlled area east midlands 23 kilometers currently i'm in the controlled area
of east midlands it's 23 kilometers away from me and if i now press the comma key on the keyboard
30 kilometers safe altitude
240 m which is 174 m above it tells me the current safe altitude uh circle i'm 30 kilometers away
from the airport or more so the self set 30 kilometers safe altitude is safe altitude 240
m which is 240 meters uh that's good to know i could then use the auto auto altitude to descend
to the altitude if i wanted to i can also press period which tells me 617 above ground how high
above ground i currently am 617 meters
94 and 94 semicolon is the current sea level height above sea level of the terrain 711 and 711
z no y y sorry y is my altitude 66 kilometers manchester three minutes
zero comma one left at three twenty seven comma seven three twenty seven comma seven
slash three twenty okay let me uh ahead of time let me switch my radio frequency to
manchester's approach control because i can remember it if i didn't i could look it up in the
airport properties but i know it's 135.0 set frequency 135 dashboard window so that i don't
i'll be alerted and the airport will greet me as soon as i get within range which is 50 kilometers
in this case because it's a category 3 airport you can configure this in settings as well by the way
but i have it set so that category 3 airports uh can be contacted when i'm 50 kilometers or less
far away from them 52 kilometers so the tower is going to contact us really shortly when it
does i'm going to ask for a runway assignment and then immediately for an approach clearance
way dash 4 sk696 you've been assigned runway zero five zero five left approach six nine six
six you can't begin approach let's slow down you're zero let's turn off auto navigation
And let's set my course to 270, so due west.
It'll take a while for me to turn by 90 degrees.
And I have to keep checking my speed,
because I was approaching the airport on the course of 328 point something degrees.
But I was given a sign, the runway of 50, 05,
which means I now have to fly around the airport.
I have to make a circle until the airport's position in relation to me is not
334 degrees, but due 50.
Once it's due 50, I can turn to face it straight, directly, head-on.
And that'll be the proper course that I need to be flying at
in order to land and to reach the runway.
So I can already start descending a bit as well.
The current safe altitude circle for 50 kilometers is 545 meters.
So let's set my auto altitude to something a little higher.
Let's do 548, maybe.
So I'm descending a bit.
772.
852.
548.
544.
Set altitude.
547.
I don't want to be below the safe altitude.
549.
549, that's a bit too high.
544.
400.
Set altitude.
500.
548.
Excellent.
Let's leave it at that.
33 kilometers, Manchester, two minutes.
673.
90 right at zero.
The airport is now straight off to my right at position zero.
400.
Let's turn a little closer to the 300.
Auto course with Alt-S.
My speed is now still okay.
My altitude is now okay.
83 right at seven.
33 kilometers.
Man, the distance is still okay.
And the airport is moving ever farther off to the right.
I need to get it to be on course 50 before I turn to face it straight.
72 right at 12.
488 above ground.
I'm still 488 meters above ground.
548.
At the altitude of 548 meters, so everything's going fine so far.
76 right at 16.
514.
78 right at 18.
I need to...
So I need...
Now at this point, I need to keep checking my speed.
I need to keep checking my speed.
So that I don't stall.
And I also need to keep checking the position of the airport in relation to my...
81 right at 21.
Current course.
482.
The current stall speed without flaps, without any flaps, is 380.
So I need to...
84 right at 24.
Raise the flaps in time.
460.
So that I don't stall.
But I can't raise them too early either.
Because if I did, I could...
Damage them.
86 right at 26.
Because the speed would be too high.
445.
88 right at 28.
437.
300.
89 right at 29.
500.
I've turned to zero now.
Zero.
428.
422.
419.
416.
71 right at 32.
411.
408.
I think it's safe to set the flaps to position 2 for landing, which decreases the stall speed
from 380 kilometers per hour to 320 kilometers per hour.
394 flaps extended downwards to 2.
I did it perfectly.
So I can still keep slowing down because the current landing speed is...
Combo box.
Sort of.
Cruising speed.
Current stall.
Current takeoff.
Current landing speed.
278 kilometers.
278 kilometers per hour.
37 right at 37.
I also need to...
500.
Keep checking the...
380 flaps extended downwards.
Downwards to 2.
The position of the...
377 flaps extended downwards to 2.
Of the airport.
38 right at 38.
North.
I still have time.
38 right at 38.
I...
As you...
As I said before, I needed to be...
39 right at 39.
At course 50.
366 flaps extended downwards to 2.
250.
365.
40 right at 40.
Set course.
25.
25 now.
359 flaps extended downwards to 2.
25.
25 right at 41.
351 flaps extended downwards to 2.
359 flaps extended downwards to 2.
Okay.
25.
17 right at 42.
Airport is at 42.
8 more degrees.
I needed to move by 8 more degrees.
344 flaps extended downwards to 2.
344.
That's still a bit too high of a speed.
17 right at 42.
I need the speed to get to like 325 and then I'll extend the flaps further to position
4 for landing.
336 flaps extended downwards.
So...
So that I'll be safe to keep slowing down to 278, 279 or what it was, the landing speed.
The current landing speed.
Okay, let's do flaps for landing to position 4.
Flaps set.
I did it, yes.
Without any stalling.
25.
20 right at 45.
21 kilometers, Manchester.
21 kilometers.
I'm a little bit closer than I wanted to be, but no wonder, considering that I'm also talking to you and describing everything as I go, everything that I'm doing.
21 right at 46.
312 flaps extended downwards to 4.
I'm a little bit stressed out, but not too much.
I believe I will be able to make it in time.
22 right at 47.
Three more degrees.
Come on, come on, come on.
307 flaps extended downwards to 4.
307.
20 more or something.
30 more to slow down.
23 right at 48.
307.
304 flaps extended downwards to 24 right at 49.
24 right at...
302 flaps...
24 right at 49.
500.
I'm going to choke the speed for now, because I need to focus on turning now.
25 right at 50.
Turn right, 25 degrees.
Zero.
Three right at 51.
Oh, no.
I screwed it up.
So, let me...
Let me...
500.
Zero.
20.
30.
Zero.
400.
15.
Zero.
20.
300.
200.
100.
150.
200.
Change course.
Radio off.
Communicator off.
Atlas off.
And I was turning too sharply.
I panicked.
You can't just...
Turn the wheels.
You can't just turn the wheels or wings.
Flight evaluation dialogue.
Edit flight.
I mean, on the ground, you can bank the wheels by up to 50 degrees to either left or right.
Obviously.
But while flying, you can only bank the wings by up to 25 degrees.
If you do more, if you panic like I just did...
You can do more.
You can set the bank angle of the wings to like 50.
But if you do, that's just too steep of a bank angle.
You will not be able to recover from that anymore.
And it's just an unrecoverable stall all the way to the ground, like what just happened.
So flight evaluation.
You can...
We can read the flight evaluation.
Flight length 272 kilometers.
Flight duration 33 minutes.
Points minus 10.
It's a real shame because we were almost...
Almost about to land successfully.
Earnings minus 20, minor crashes zero, penalty points one.
Started engines without permission.
Cause of fatal stall, bank angle too steep.
Cause of fatal stall, bank angle too steep, blank, blank.
Dashboard window.
Press enter to quit.
Free flights.
But you know what?
I know I said I wouldn't be editing anything out, which I won't, but I've changed my mind.
I can't just let end this here like that.
I can't.
And I can't allow myself to end the recording with a crash, with a stall.
So what I'm about to do, I'm going to take exactly, literally the same flight with the same plane from the same airport to the same airport.
I'm going to pause the recording here and I'm going to resume it again.
Um, when I'm turning and descending to align myself with the landing runway, obviously I'll be having a different call sign this time.
But I will do it again this time and I will do it proper because I can't, I don't want to let you down.
And I don't want to, I don't want to let myself down while I've already let the 217 or how many passengers I had down who are dead now.
But I believe that everyone deserves a second chance, including myself.
So in order to finish this recording in a, on a happy note and a successful note, um, I'll be right back with you.
When I'm in the air again and I'm about to, um, face the, the airport, the landing runway.
All right, I'm back.
I'm 27 kilometers away from Manchester, a little bit farther away than before.
330 flaps extended.
330, let me do flaps for landing to position four because style speed is 320 at the moment.
And current landing speed is...
Current landing speed, 275.
275, and let me focus on piloting, only on piloting for now a little bit so that I don't crash again.
I've explained the principle anyway, and I'll explain the rest as I go.
316 flaps extended downwards to four.
We should be fine to go now.
30 kilometers safe altitude 545M, which is 474M above ground.
As long as I don't, don't screw up anything.
311 flaps extended downwards to four.
18 right at 43.
Okay.
25.
So I can't turn, I can't start turning too sharply like I did before, or I'm going to stall.
303 flaps extended downwards to four.
275, yeah, is landing speed.
Okay.
19 right at 44.
25.
22 kilometers Manchester, four minutes.
299 flaps extended downwards to four.
Still closer than I would like to be.
20 right at 45.
But never mind.
25.
295 flaps extended downwards to four.
20 more kilometers to slow down.
21 right at 46.
293 flaps extended downwards to four.
This is really difficult to concentrate and to talk at the same time, and I have to concentrate here.
22 right at 47.
290 flaps extended downwards to four.
I don't want to screw up.
22 right at 47.
288 flaps extended downwards to four.
286 flaps extended downwards to four.
23 right at 48.
If I have at least 280.
284 flaps extended downwards to four.
I can choke the engines and keep it going.
281 flaps extended.
281 flaps.
24 right at 49.
280 flaps extended downwards to four.
500.
Choked off.
24 right at 49.
Excellent.
25 right at 50.
Now.
Course 40.
43.
Zero.
Dead ahead at 50.
Yes, dead ahead at 50.
279 flaps extended downwards to four.
279.
279 is my current speed, which is OK.
I can land at 279 kilometers per hour.
Dead ahead at 50.
16 kilometers, though.
I know I can already descend to 108 meters altitude when I'm aligned with the runway because I remember it.
But if I didn't, I could look it up in the airport properties.
Let's set the flaps.
400.
For landing all the way up to six.
So that I can brake as fast as I can.
Let's lower the landing gear with Control-G.
300.
I'm still descending in the meantime.
Climb.
Collision with the ground.
13 kilometers.
Manchester.
Two minutes.
13 kilometers.
Manchester.
Two minutes.
Yeah, GPWS is warning me of an imminent collision with the ground, but I know it's an OK altitude.
I'll still be like 70 meters above the ground.
130.
120.
And it's safe to be this low when aligned with the runway.
Climb.
90.
Imminent.
80.
71 above ground.
Yeah.
One right at 51.
Climb.
Collision with the ground.
Imminent.
One right at 51.
11 kilometers.
Manchester.
Two minutes.
Climb.
Collision with the ground.
Imminent.
Zip.
One right at 51.
50.
Climb.
Collision with the ground.
Imminent.
51 above ground.
That's all good.
When I'm 5 kilometers away from the airport, I can press control S to invoke the ILS system.
Which runway do I have?
Climb.
Collision with the ground.
Imminent.
Oh no.
Dashboard window.
Oh.
Runway.
05 right.
Climb.
Collision with the ground.
Imminent.
ILS will offer.
You know what?
GPWS off.
ILS.
ILS will offer.
GPWS off.
ILS will offer the runways that are available.
Meaning 05L or 05R.
And when I choose one, so 05 right, the runway will start sending out a radio beacon of some
kind, which then auto guides my plane in order to stay on course, stay aligned with the runway.
But it can only be done.
Only be done.
05L collapse.
05R.
Dashboard window.
Yes.
Only be done when I'm close enough to the airport.
1 right at 51.
Now you can, if I check my course, you can hear.
51,2 ILS.
That I'm 51.2 on course 51.2, but it says ILS, meaning I'm being guided.
1 right at 51.
3,6KM Manchester.
To the airport.
Okay.
I should be.
279 flaps extended downwards to 6.
I should actually be okay.
Last system.
Length.
Landing gear lowered.
Dashboard.
Gear lowered.
Altitude is.
279 flaps extended downwards to 6.
Speed is okay.
Flaps are okay.
Direction is okay.
1 right at 51.
Since I'm.
51,1 ILS.
On ILS.
14.
Alright.
1,9KM Manchester.
0 minutes.
In Eurofly 3 you can't just, you know, land anywhere near the airport and just lower
the nose.
You have to be aligned with the runway like I just did.
You have to be no more than 20 meters above the ground, otherwise you would stall and
break the plane.
0,5KM.
If you are.
Let me.
Get.
20 meters above the ground only.
Runway 0.
20.
And land.
When you're 20 above ground, you lower.
You.
10.
Level the nose.
Level the nose and set the engines all the way down to 0 and essentially let the plane
fall.
Taxi mode.
85 flaps extended.
82 flaps.
79 flaps extended.
Moving slash.
64 flaps.
All the way to 50.
58.
Kilometers per hour.
55.
Flaps.
54.
53.
52.
51.
Flaps.
50.
Extended.
Choke off.
49 flaps extended downwards to 6.
19.
65m.
44m.
We have 19.
44 meters left.
50,0 ILS.
Of the runway ahead of us, which is perfect.
We're on course because ILS is guiding us.
49 flaps extended downwards to 6.
And it's excellent because we did it without having to stop all the way.
As it should be.
If you've ever flown on a plane in real life, you'll have noticed that the plane did not
just stop, you know, after landing, brake all the way to a full stop, and then pick
up less speed again.
1.
Power.
0,0%.
Gear 1.
Taxi mode.
Yeah, we're in taxi mode.
49 flaps extended downwards to 6.
Flaps for landing.
Oh, and I forgot.
I believe I forgot to ask for the clearance to land.
Taxi lights off.
Landing lights on.
Yeah.
I forgot about the taxi and landing lights, to turn off taxi lights after takeoff, to
turn on landing lights before landing, and I forgot to ask for the clearance to land,
which is pretty bad.
But it shouldn't be happening.
cost. We essentially landed without clearance, so I believe, I'm almost sure, I'm going to get
penalized with penalty points for that. We'll see it in the end, in the flight evaluation,
but never mind. Things like that happen. Let's switch our frequency to Manchester Ground Control
118.6. Let's slow down and let's ask them to assign us a gate. We're supposed to taxi to
stand 1 to onboard our passengers. All right. Let's slow down to 20 now, 20 kilometers per hour
to make our movement faster, if we went, safer, to make our movement safer, because if we were
going faster, then we would have to go faster. So, let's slow down and let's ask them to assign
that. We may not be able to turn by 90 degrees on time. We still have 368 meters of runway
ahead of us to go. We're supposed to go to stand 1, was it? Yes. The next runway ahead of us,
because I know this airport, I know it's going to be Yankee and it's going to be facing due east.
The turning is going to be due east. We're currently on course,
50, but Yankee is a north-south taxiway. So, I'm going to need to turn to get to the runway
to turn due east. And then when I do, when I am on the runway, I need to turn by 90 more degrees
to the right to be facing due south. That'll lead me to the Sierra taxiway. Then I'll need
to traverse that. That'll lead me to Delta. Then I'll need to turn again and traverse Delta.
All the way to Mike and to Zulu. And Zulu will finally lead me to the stands. Here we go.
The Yankee taxiway on our right at course 90, 0, 0, 95. Oh, 94, 93, 92, 91 east. And now turn all the way to go south.
119. 20 flaps extended downwards to 142.
152. 160. 169. 0. 182. 181. 181. South. 0. 100. 100. 100. South. 0. South. 1924m.
1924 meters, so we can speed up all the way to 50 kilometers per hour again to traverse
the Yankee faster. We're now going due south. You can check the angle, the back angle of
your nose at any time with T.
34 flaps. 35 flaps. 36 flaps extended downwards to 6.
Of your wheels while on the ground or wings while airborne with T at any, with G at any
time.
47 flaps. 48. 49. 49. 50 flaps extended downwards to 6.
And if you press T twice rapidly in short succession, you level the nose. And if you
press G twice rapidly, you level the wings or wheels. So that's how it works.
1500 in 9F.
Still 1.5 kilometers left.
0.5.
And let's check our coordinates.
1854 Yankee.
We're still all the way up north.
2550 Yankee.
And even more farther to the right to the east.
Uh, because the coordinates, they tell you the name of the taxiway, or the runway that
you're currently moving on, but the coordinate system, the numbering, the entire numbering
refers to the whole overall, uh, area, and size of the airport.
15. 50 flaps extended downwards to 6.
1062m.
You can see that our south-north coordinate is decreasing, so we're going south, and we
can see in the coordinates that we're actually getting closer and closer to the south part,
south edge of the airport.
Oh my god, let me slow down.
Because our turning to Sierra is coming, I believe that'll be on our right, we'll be
going west.
It's still okay, I'm panicking needlessly.
Oh, I don't want to crash or leave the runway.
Because I didn't turn in time, because that would also earn me more penalty points, but
other than that, we're pretty safe now, now that we're just on the ground and only taxiing
along the airport.
Still 291 meters of Yankee to go.
Pretty fine.
We're going south.
Okay, everything's fine.
I'm just triple and quadruple checking everything at this point, because I really don't want
to have to redo this whole thing all over again.
But I think we're fine.
I'm way more nervous than my passengers are, I hope, and that's exactly how it should be.
So you see, this airport has a different layout.
It has the runways 05, 0523, 0523 is a one, 0523L or 0523R, and the, they're not beginning
straight at Delta.
We have to go through these Sierra and Yankee taxiways in order to get to the runways.
Oh, so that's why you need to...
249.
Sierra.
257.
262.
Sierra.
Learn the...
273.
274.
275.
276.
0.
390.
Sierra.
Uh, yeah.
276.
200.
2002.
0.
274.
273.
272.
271.
West.
216.
200.
West.
2...
The layout of each airport, uh, individually.
Preferably before landing on it, or before taking off from it, while you still have time,
uh, by looking at its properties as I was describing before.
Now, uh, two, two kilometers of Sierra ahead.
We're going 22 West.
Okay.
And you can see...
And you can see that our coordinates are staying the same.
396, the latitude, meaning we're pretty low down in the southern part of the airport by now.
Now it's our longitude, the west to east coordinate, that is decreasing.
Since we're going, we were all the way to the east and we're not going west.
So it's decreasing, we're moving essentially more to the left part, to the left edge of the airport.
Let me speed up a bit more again, because this is taking forever.
I hope the passengers are having a good time at least.
Well, let me do about, because I got pretty relieved by the fact that I was able to land and not crash this time around, which is pretty good.
Let me speed up a bit more.
55 flaps, 56, 57, 57, 58 flaps, 59, 60 flaps, 60 flaps, 61 flaps, 61 flaps, 62 flaps, 63 flaps extended down.
300.
296 Sierra, 1261M.
Still over 1.2, almost 1.3 kilometers to go on Sierra.
Excuse me.
1037M.
Then we'll be coming to Delta, and we're about to get to Mike and to Zulu and to the stands.
We're supposed to go to stand 1, right?
SK624, taxi to stand 1.
Yes.
763M, gear 0.
That's right.
Slow down to 20 again.
54 flaps extended downwards to 6.
49 flaps extended downward.
584M.
42 flaps extended downwards to 6.
Because we don't want to pass the junction.
36 flaps extended downwards to 6.
Because you can't turn 180 degrees with such a large plane.
The.
The taxiways and runways are too narrow for that.
Even on high speeds, you would leave the runway anyway.
The tower will tell you that it is the case, and it would tell you to get back to your
path and you would get a penalty point.
One penalty point per one runway departure.
Like if you're moving outside of the designated runway or taxiway numbers, names, in a basically
undefined area of the airport, like in the grass, beyond the runways, that's a penalty
point.
That's not supposed to be happening.
152M.
West.
Going to West on Sierra.
There's the turning to Delta.
And we'll be turning left.
West.
When we get to Delta, we need to reach it first.
We need the name to be announced, like the zone that we are currently in.
And once it is, we can't be doing due west anymore, because Delta is a south-north taxiway.
Turning left.
258.
To go due south again.
It's zero.
Dis ofere mak strain 0.
60.
0.
16.
179.
101.
One hunt.
South.
Zero.
116M.
That was...
103M.
Pure work.
There's Alpha.
We need to be going east along Alpha, because we don't want to be going West.
So, we'll turn left.
90 left.
Once again, as soon as we're on Alpha, now.
And that'll lead us to Mike.
Mike, Mike, Mike, Mike, Mike, we want to go...
We need to go south again.
Mike.
162.
181.
South.
624m.
And this is going to take us to Zulu.
If we passed the Zulu junction, we would be going to the hangars, which we can't.
We can't park the plane in the hangar yet because we need to onboard the passengers first.
There's the Zulu junction to our left, due east.
20 flaps extended downwards to 6.
Zulu.
98.
90.
Due east.
No.
Now it's due east.
660m.
Gear 0.
And...
18 flaps extended downwards to 6.
Is it going to be stand 5 first?
Or stand 1 first?
On this airport.
I don't remember.
15 flaps extended.
14 flaps extended downwards.
13 flaps extended.
So let me slow down.
13 flaps.
12 flaps.
11 flaps.
So that I don't overrun it.
Which one is it?
Come on.
Stand 1.
1.
Oh, okay.
Stand 1.
Better.
It's a good thing that I slowed down.
Stand 1.
39.
I need to turn due north.
I won't probably be able to make it.
But I can stop anywhere in the stand.
That's the benefit.
Stand 1.
I will be able to make it.
Okay.
Stand 1.
300.
North.
0.
Drake.
Full stop.
16.
Stand 1.
447.
Wonderful.
I can turn off the sensor because it's annoying.
Sensor off.
I won't be moving anywhere anyway.
Anymore.
North.
I know that I'm...
So I actually probably turned a bit too early and I'm close to the right side, right edge
of the stand.
But since the stands are essentially free to drive through, nothing would happen.
I would just leave the stand.
But if this happened in a gate, if I was in a gate and I kept going right or turning right,
as I was saying at the very beginning, I would just crash into the gate and get wrecked.
So.
Let me park.
Parking brake on.
Engage the parking brake.
Let me open the cockpit door so that we can hear everything better.
Our happy passengers, who seem to be okay.
Let me ask the tower to onboard them.
And let me...
Hey.
downward eight flaps extended downward 15 can happen any time
12 flaps 12 flaps 13th 13th 14th 14th 15th 15th 16th 16th 17th 17th gear 0 choked off
54 58 60 69 79 89 97 0 100 101 101 100 100 99 99 99 98 98 97 97 97 96 96 96 95
95 94 now on the 94 93 92 92 91 area as you can hear 15 flaps extend gear 0
you
choked off gear 0
134 0 okay i'm standing totally like parallel not straight at all in the stand but i'm in the
stand uh let's not 44 stand 3 let's not tempt it any further 629 stand 3 so let's try this again
engage the parking brakes parking brakes on open the cockpit doors
50 document ask the tower to onboard them already finally onboard dashboards 64 starting
unboarding thank you open the doors the captain doors for them so that they can get the hell
out opened and you know what i believe we can turn off the engines stopping stopping and the
ventilation off cabin pressurization off temperature control off tcas off stall indication off
and the battery radio off transponder off taxi lights off done
Cabin lights off, strobe lights off, storm radar off,
computer off, communicator off, atlas off.
And unfasten our seatbelt.
Seatbelt unfastened.
Because we don't need to do anything anymore.
We don't even need the radio for anything,
because as soon as they get out, the flight will be over,
we'll be ranked and evaluated.
We did not do as good as I hoped to, but never mind,
because it could have turned out worse, too.
I could have spent more attempts than just two
on recording this, you know.
I'm basically just glad it turned out the way it did,
even though I crashed the first time.
Now, we have finally safely arrived in our destination,
and that's the only thing that counts in the end.
The only thing that matters in history
is never gonna ask about the first attempt.
We'll pretend it did not happen,
and let's just pretend that it didn't happen.
And let's just pretend it never did.
Oh, let's just forget it ever did.
Flight completed.
You have leveled up.
I've closed the doors.
I have leveled up.
I've completed the flight.
The passengers are safe in their final destination,
and I can have a day off as a pilot.
I can go get a beer or something.
But before I do that, let's take a look
at the flight evaluation together.
Flight evaluation.
Successful flight.
Like I said, that's what counts.
That's what matters, not the crash before.
Shush, what are you talking about?
What crash?
There was no crash, ever.
Successful flight.
Flight length, 295 kilometers.
Flight duration, 48 minutes.
Points, one.
Let me see.
I even gained a point.
Gained a point, OK?
Earnings, one.
And I earned one euro.
Minor crashes, zero.
Penalty points, zero.
So I, yeah.
Because, yeah, but of course, because I did not, ever, ever,
because I did not, ever, like, depart the runway
without permission, or enter the runway without permission,
or start the engines without permission.
Blink, blink.
I did not do anything.
So you know what?
I know you keep repeating the word crash,
but what are you talking about?
The flight was a complete success.
And there was no mistakes or errors, ever.
It was the golden standard of how
flights in Eurofly 3 should be done.
Even with category 3 airplanes, which I don't even own anymore,
which I don't even own yet.
But who cares about that, you know?
It's like, what matters is that you saw, no, no, no.
All joking aside.
Press Enter to quit.
Free flights.
Let's get back to the main menu.
All jokes aside, I hope, I really sincerely
hope you've enjoyed this, because it was, after all,
a complete flight from start to finish, as it should be,
everything included, all the steps in the checklist
that you need to do in order for
your flight to be successful in the end.
Well, besides my asking for the landing clearance,
and besides the taxi lights and landing lights.
But these are actually quite minor infractions
that, as you can see, I was not even penalized for.
I should actually be penalized for landing
without clearance I'm probably going to report that one as a bug but other than that I think
it turned out pretty okay considering all I had to do and all I had to explain in the meantime
with literally almost no waiting for me to finish my explanations so that was it that was your the
first official English demonstration of Eurofly 3 for you almost half a year well not almost
exactly half a year after the Slovak one we were actually genuinely believing by the time the
Slovak one which which is still available on this YouTube channel was published we did actually
believe it's like a matter of a couple days or a couple weeks at the very most for the game to
come out and to get released but as I was saying before real life schedules were getting in the way
as well as more bugs to fix more bugs that were being discovered
more new
features or changes really important and necessary ones that were being asked for for example the the
landing process the way you land as I was just demonstrating a while ago the way it's currently
done in a version 3 was still different and it was it was still the old one from version 2 by
the time the Slovak presentation was being recorded so that's that's it for you that's
the English demo for you hope you liked it you found it entertaining by the way and I hope you
enjoyed it and I'll see you in the next one bye bye
not only that but I also hope that it actually taught you or showed you the very basic principles
of how to start doing things so that you have at least a rough idea of how things done how things
are done and what is what once you start playing the game for yourself in a couple days or maybe
even now if you've discovered this recording a bit later on because on the day of its publishing
that's when the series of audio recordings is starting to be published one recording per day
the whole audio tutorial series all the 15 basic recordings in the basic series as I was saying at
the beginning and once those are out and released it's time for the closed private beta so things
are definitely moving on
I know some of you who were familiar with Eurofly before and may have been waiting for version 3 may have had your doubts or may have lost faith in the development team and may have started thinking that no version 3 is ever going to to come out at all ever and that it's all just empty promises so I hope this recording helps you helps at least partially to
to
eliminate
that doubt and for those of you who have never even played Eurofly before at all who have discovered the game for the first time via this recording but got interested and excited about the game and can't wait to try it hands-on for yourself I wish you the best of success the best of luck as few crashes and stalls as possible I hope I wish you to become a good pilot soon and perhaps better than I am soon
to become a good pilot soon and perhaps better than I am soon
than I am soon
and I can't wait to meet you in the air at work each of us flying
at work each of us flying
to our respective destinations and perhaps to have a chat on the communicator
that was your first official
English Eurofly 3 demo for you my name is Lucas I'm part of the development team
I hope you liked it
Thanks for watching or listening
Thanks for listening
and see you next time in one of the next videos of this episode, bye bye see you next time in one of the next videos, bye bye
recordings or in Eurofly 3 itself.